okay so I'll try not to I'll try to just
好吧，所以我会尽量不要
sort of blaze through this as best as
尽力而为
quickly as I can so basically I'm just
尽可能快地基本上我只是
gonna try and give you a quick update on
会尝试给您快速更新
where things are with the with the eat
吃东西在哪里
jacquard ee8 delivery there's a lot of
提花ee8交付有很多
activity if you're subscribed to any
活动，如果您已订阅
mailing lists or or watching any github
邮件列表或观看任何github
projects I'm sure you've seen you know a
项目，我确定您已经了解了
some smattering of discourse going back
一些话语往后追溯
and forth
来回
it certainly has ramped up in the past
过去肯定会增加
several weeks so good great to see all
几个星期真好，很高兴看到所有
that progress the the just to sort of
进步的正义
get us back to where we were last month
让我们回到上个月的状态
right the deliverables for jacquard e8
提花e8的交付物正确
haven't changed at all right we're still
完全没有改变，我们仍然
planning to deliver a complete set of
计划提供一套完整的
Jakarta e8 specifications and these will
Jakarta e8规格，这些将
each consist of a specification document
每个都包含一个规范文档
I'll talk a little more about that in a
我将在
minute the new API release which is
分钟的新API版本
programmatically will be unchanged from
从程序上将保持不变
what we did with the the the Java EE 8
我们对Java EE 8所做的工作
release it will include a new T so
发布它将包含一个新的T
that's oh it's a new API with that
哦，这是一个新的API
licensed under eclipse EPO and using all
在Eclipse EPO下获得许可并使用全部
the Eclipse development process will
Eclipse开发过程将
have tcks there are where we have
有t子，我们在那里
produced to essentially make the same
生产基本相同
collection of tests that we used in Java
我们在Java中使用的测试集合
EE releases but now they're there
EE发布，但现在就在那里
they're testing further on compatibility
他们正在进一步测试兼容性
with Jaccard EE and we're essentially
使用Jaccard EE，我们从本质上讲
introducing this new component this new
介绍这个新的组件这个新的
idea about what's called a compatible
关于所谓兼容的想法
implementation and so in that again I'll
实施，因此我再次
talk a little I think I'll talk a little
谈一点我想我会谈一点
bit about that and a following slide so
关于那一点和随后的幻灯片
the specification process this is
规范过程是
following the the eclipse foundation
遵循日食基础
specification prior process you might
您可能需要先说明规格
see that that as
看到那样
um abbreviated EF SP he yeah
嗯，缩写为EF SP，是的
and one thing is there's a brand new
一件事是有一个全新的
version that was just ratified and as I
我刚刚批准的版本
think it's posted on the Eclipse
认为它发布在Eclipse上
specifications project and then uh along
规格项目，然后沿着
with that we've also done a rev on the
以此，我们还对
jacquard EEE specification process so
提花电子电气设备规格流程
what the way Eclipse makes this work is
Eclipse使这项工作的方式是
there's a sort of a master process that
有一种主过程
it's the Eclipse Foundation
这是Eclipse基金会
specification process and then there's a
规范过程，然后有一个
then each specification project can add
然后每个规范项目可以添加
their own sort of special nuances to the
他们对自己的特殊细微差别
overall process all right so we've just
整个过程还可以，所以我们只是
ratified a new version of that I don't
批准了我没有的新版本
think it wasn't posted yesterday it's
认为它不是昨天发布的
probably going to get up be put up
可能会起床
pretty real soon but I put some put a
很快就很真实了，但我放了一些
link in it they both of these links have
链接中，它们两个都有
not changed from what they were before
与以前相比没有变化
have them in a web page but you know in
将它们放在网页中，但您知道
the interest of time I'll just sort of
为了时间的利益，我只会
skip that for now and I think the the
现在就跳过它，我认为
main thing the least as the sort of you
最重要的是你
know worried about trying to get this
知道担心要得到这个
out on time the main thing that's
准时
updated in the new jacquard EEE
在新的提花EEE中进行了更新
specification is we've dropped the
规范是我们放弃了
minimum ballot period from 30 days to
最小投票期从30天到
two weeks so that should give us a
两个星期，所以应该给我们一个
little bit of breathing time
一点呼吸时间
this project okay so the specifications
这个项目好，所以规格
our goal is if you have a Java EE eight
我们的目标是如果您有Java EE 8
implementation you should be able to
实施您应该能够
just unpack the new tcks and run them in
只需打开新包装，然后将其放入即可
exactly the same way you ran them before
与您之前运行它们的方式完全相同
and you should be able to achieve a
并且您应该能够实现
compatibility you know compatibility
兼容性，你知道兼容性
test output that matches what you had in
测试与您的输出匹配的输出
Java EE eight that's a key goal of this
Java EE八是此目标
release let's see we have finished
发布，让我们看看我们已经完成了
revive it revising all of the the
复兴它修订所有的
specification projects so now there if
规格项目，所以现在在那里
you go and look at the specifications oh
你去看看规格哦
great that's going to open on the wrong
太棒了，这将打开错误的道路
window so alright so when you look at
窗户很好，所以当你看着
the forge a top-level project page over
在上方建立顶层专案页面
here on the right side you see a whole
在右侧，您会看到一个整体
bunch of them new product well many
他们很多新产品
projects are here a lot of them has
项目在这里很多
changed names and essentially everything
更改名称，基本上所有内容
that starts with Jakarta is now I think
我认为从雅加达开始
that's a pretty good metric here is now
这是一个相当不错的指标
a special an API specification project
一个特殊的API规范项目
and this these will all these all
这些都会全部
constitute the the the sort of the
构成那种
collection of Jakarta api's they are and
雅加达api的集合，他们是和
every one of them is staged poised and
他们每个人都准备好了
ready for a release that's what that's
准备发布那是什么
um gonna come up and our target dates
嗯，我们会来和我们的目标日期
still the same September 10th right in
还是在9月10日
these slides and I'll put the I'll send
这些幻灯片，然后我将发送
I'll push the post these to the same
我会把这些推到相同的位置
place we hadn't posted them last month
我们上个月没有发布的地方
we will be creating balanced submissions
我们将创建平衡的提交
they were the the intent is to use the
他们的意图是使用
github pull request to to as a way of
github将请求拉至作为一种方式
submitting them and then tracking the
提交它们，然后跟踪
approvals and I listed a couple of them
批准，我列出了其中的几个
I I list a couple of these pull requests
II列出了其中一些拉取请求
here just so we
在这里，所以我们
you know so if you want to if you're
你知道吗，如果你想
interested in sort of voyeurism and you
对偷窥感兴趣，而你
just want to watch these projects you
只想看这些项目你
could just watch this project Jakarta AE
可以看这个项目雅加达AE
/ specifications
/规格
just look for pull requests and over
只是寻找拉取请求和结束
time you'll see more and more of the
时间，您将会看到越来越多的
specifications themselves show up here
规格本身显示在这里
and you can you can actually open any
而且你可以打开任何一个
one of these and each of them has this
其中之一，每个人都有
nice collection of them of checkboxes
他们的复选框很好的集合
all those need to be satisfied and when
所有这些都需要满足，何时
they're all checked off I think they
他们都被检查了我想他们
believe that that means that that
相信那意味着
specification has been proved we have a
规格已经证明我们有一个
I mentioned the jacquard EEA tcks so
我提到提花EEAEA
from a test perspective these are
从测试的角度来看，这些是
identical to what used to be licensed to
与以前被许可使用的相同
Java EE licensees and those T CK's are
Java EE被许可方和那些T CK是
all running right now we have we have
现在所有我们都在运行
essentially have the same level of of
本质上具有相同的水平
operational you know reliability as we
可操作，您知道可靠性，因为我们
had with them with Java EE accepted
与他们一起接受了Java EE
they're now all open sourced and you can
他们现在都是开源的，你可以
you could download the test versions
您可以下载测试版本
they're available right now or you can
它们现在可用，或者您可以
um once they're a part approved as part
嗯，一旦他们被批准为一部分
of the specification process there will
规范过程将
be a a Eclipse Foundation specification
成为Eclipse Foundation规范
license version for people that want to
想要的人的许可证版本
use the you know to seek an official
用你认识的人去找官员
Jakarta ee branding sorry not not
雅加达EE品牌推广很抱歉没有
running my computer correctly alright so
正确运行我的计算机
we've done a lot with the TC k set up
我们在设置TC k方面做了很多工作
many of the API projects are now are
现在有许多API项目
busy incorporating TCK test jobs in
忙于将TCK测试工作并入
directly into their jacquard ee
直接进入提花机
processes i listed a couple of of the
我列出了几个
pull requests that people i've are using
拉取我正在使用的人的请求
to to sort of document how these things
来整理这些东西如何
are integrated beyond simple out of
整合超越简单
our Prague office has been instrumental
我们的布拉格办事处发挥了重要作用
in trying to get these set up I think
在尝试建立这些设置时，我认为
we've got Pyrus created several of these
我们Pyrus创建了其中几个
running in there in projects that
在那里运行的项目
they're leaders on IBM has created
他们是IBM创建的领导者
several of the use of the running lead
跑带的几种使用
on
上
and I don't mean if I didn't mention
我不是说我不提
your organization that doesn't mean
您的组织并不意味着
anything it's just those were the two
就是那两个
that I could think of right away so if
我可以马上想到的
you want to watch things right I would
你想看的东西我会
say
说
start with them get up calm the main
从他们开始起床冷静主要
project and pick an API project that
项目并选择一个API项目
you're interested in and you know use
您感兴趣并且知道使用
the github watch button there's an awful
github watch按钮有一个可怕的
lot of back and forth discussion that
很多来回的讨论
goes along that's associated with the
伴随着与
pull requests and with issues there are
拉请求和有问题
there's a giant collection of mailing
有大量的邮件收集
lists that are available on available
可用清单
from eclipse the thing is that you know
从月食的事情是，你知道
the the data from those two don't really
那两个的数据不是真的
intermingle so if you want the full view
混合在一起，所以如果您想欣赏全貌
you may need to subscribe to both for
您可能需要同时订阅
the projects that you're interested in
您感兴趣的项目
and if and then you want to watch these
如果然后您想看这些
PRS pull requests to the github Jakari
PRS将请求拉至github Jakari
specifications project that's where
规格项目在哪里
you'll see the specifications flowing in
您会看到规格不断涌入
alright and I'm now at my deadline so
好吧，我现在是截止日期，所以
just continue to remind people if you if
只是继续提醒别人，如果你
you are interested in contributing to
您有兴趣为
jacquard EEE you don't need to be a
提花EEE，您无需成为
developer there's an awful lot of
开发人员有很多
writing level things right we still have
写作水平的东西，我们仍然有
to get websites created for most of
为大多数网站创建网站
these projects we have a template and a
这些项目，我们有一个模板和一个
a mechanism in place for so for rolling
适当的滚动机制
up all that all of their websites but we
他们所有的网站，但我们
do need people just too that are that
确实也需要人
have some skills with them setting up
设置一些技巧
web K websites and and maybe you know
Web K网站，也许您知道
can either write text for them or maybe
可以为他们写文字或者
can write them you know can put them
可以写他们，你知道可以把它们
into into markdown flavored pages we can
进入降价标记的页面，我们可以
certainly use help for all of that the
当然可以使用所有帮助
the set of
的一组
for forums joining him to project is the
与他一起参与项目的论坛是
same as it was you know has it's been I
和你知道的一样
think with the coups for years
与政变思考多年
right um anyone can subscribe to the
嗯，任何人都可以订阅
mailing list you can always follow all
邮件列表，您可以随时关注所有
the projects and activity that's going
正在进行的项目和活动
on you don't have to have anything to
在你不需要任何东西
follow github projects except the github
关注除github以外的github项目
ID if you want to make a commit or
ID，如果您想提交或
submit a PR you do need to create an
提交您需要创建的PR
eclipse account and and you'll also need
蚀帐户，并且您还需要
an eclipse account if you want to get
蚀帐户，如果你想得到
email so I see there was some stuff in
电子邮件，所以我看到里面有些东西
chat I didn't have time to read it but I
聊天我没时间看，但是我
think that's all well that's all the
认为一切都很好
slides I have any questions about that
幻灯片我对此有任何疑问
I'm sorry it was kind of a whirlwind
对不起，有点像旋风
that was great and I don't see any
那太好了，我什么也没看到
questions in chat relevant to the
与聊天相关的问题
presentation that you made so if you
您所做的演示文稿，如果您
want to have some questions now or maybe
想要现在有一些问题，或者也许
we can we have enough time at the end of
我们可以在末尾有足够的时间
the all the presentations for questions
所有演示文稿的问题
from the audience so for developers
从观众那里，所以对于开发人员
people that are working on the
在工作的人
contributions I think the crucial thing
我认为关键的是贡献
to you know to to understand is we you
你知道要了解的是我们你
know it it may seem like some of them
知道似乎有些人
you know delivery requirements are kind
你知道送货的要求很亲切
of arduous or how can we get them done
艰巨的工作或如何完成它们
but you know we're seeing a lot of
但是你知道我们看到了很多
evidence that you know you'd see it's
您知道自己会看到的证据
straightforward enough to create all the
足够直接创建所有
all the documents that are required I
我需要的所有文件
think I mentioned earlier something
认为我之前提到过一些东西
about the specification documents in
关于规格文件
this initial round we're basically just
在最初的一轮中，我们基本上只是
relying on the collection of a sort of a
依靠某种
framing document which you know it's
您知道的框架文件
replacing what used to be the the
取代过去的
detailed specification and then a
详细规格，然后
reference to you know the the
参考你知道的
specification itself will include the
规范本身将包括
Java Docs so the API is the details
Java文档，因此API是详细信息
about how to use the api's will be only
关于如何使用api只会
in the Java Docs in this release and in
在此版本及以下版本的Java文档中
subsequent releases we will start to be
后续版本，我们将开始成为
able to bring forward the the detailed
能够提出详细
specification documents that we had in
我们拥有的规格文件
previous releases that it's taken that
以前的版本认为
that securing all the permissions and
确保所有权限并
legalese for for the the text from all
所有文本的合法文本
those previous specifications it turned
那些以前的规格
out to be a little more challenging than
挑战性要比
we anticipated so vestigation just
我们期待如此的遗迹
turned out to be a little daunting when
原来有点令人生畏
we don't it's not available
我们不是不可用
okay okay
好吧好吧
Thank You ed um Scott are you around yep
谢谢你，恩·斯科特，你在附近吗
okay perfect you see your screen yep
好吧，完美的看到你的屏幕
weekend thank you okay so just a quick
周末谢谢你好吧，所以快点
quick update on what the specification
快速更新规格
committees been up to the past ever
各个委员会都过去了
since our last call the past month and
自上个月我们上次致电以来，
primarily the focus has been on defining
重点一直放在定义
the TCK process updating order filling
TCK流程更新订单填写
out a Jakarta ad specification process
制定雅加达广告说明流程
guide and operation of the spec
规范的指导和操作
committee and then focus on what does
委员会，然后专注于做什么
that actually imply for API projects in
实际上暗示着API项目
the Jakarta e8 really so take a quick
Jakarta e8真的要花点时间
look at those three things so we just
看这三件事，我们只是
last last week we released the initial
上周，我们发布了初始
version one of the TCK process and
TCK流程的第一个版本，以及
announced it to the specification leads
向规范负责人宣布
list you can find that document here in
列表，您可以在这里找到该文档
the public public drive of the
公众的公共动力
specification committee the highlights
规格委员会的亮点
were that we define the materials for a
是我们定义了一个
TCK release which edy talked about in
edy谈论的TCK版本
his presentation we defined a process to
在他的演讲中，我们定义了一个过程
challenge TCK tests and then we defined
挑战TCK测试，然后我们定义
a process to define or to claim
定义或主张的过程
compatibility for certified
认证兼容性
implementations and the jess ops guide
实现和jess ops指南
we also made that initial draft version
我们还制作了初稿
it's not finalized but it has most of
它尚未完成，但大部分
the content they need to move forward
他们前进所需要的内容
last week as well they announced on the
他们也在上周宣布了
spec lead list and the link is here the
规格线索列表，链接在此处
highlights that we defined a number of
强调我们定义了许多
operations the suspect committee in
操作嫌疑人委员会
terms of votes and how reviews specific
投票条件以及评论的具体方式
release reviews were we're done in
发布评论是我们完成的
particular what that meant from the
特别是从
perspective of a specification project
规范项目的观点
and what it needed to do you know in
以及您需要知道什么
terms of actual details and there's a
实际细节条款，还有一个
one-page wiki that tries to collapse all
一页wiki，试图折叠全部
that information together that's listed
这些信息一起列出
here about how to prepare API projects
这里关于如何准备API项目
should be actually for Jakarta et8
应该实际上是针对雅加达et8
releases that's been updated to reflect
已更新以反映发行版
those changes in the TCK ingest ops
TCK摄取操作中的那些变化
guide it's a living document that were
指导它是一个活着的文件
we've been updating pretty much on a
我们一直在更新
daily basis as projects are going
项目进展情况
through this process and were you know
通过这个过程，你知道吗
discussing issues that are run into on
讨论碰到的问题
the on the spec leads and platform
规范线索和平台上的
development mainly lifts if you have
如果有的话，发展主要是提升
questions about that then definitely get
关于那个的问题肯定会得到
on the spec leads list and then send
在规格线索列表中，然后发送
those in or if you're not if you're not
那些在或者如果你不在的话
the lead you still have a question
领导你还有一个问题
because you're involved in the project
因为您参与了该项目
probably send it to the either get your
可能将其发送给
lead to do it or send it to the the
导致它或将其发送到
public expect committee list and that's
公众期望委员会名单，那是
pretty much what we've accomplished so
我们差不多完成了什么
far
远
thank you Scott do we have David around
谢谢你斯科特，我们身边有大卫吗
yeah I can see David's here yeah maybe
是的，我可以看到大卫在这里，也许
enter our gender pretty quickly here huh
在这里很快输入我们的性别吧
yeah I know this is unheard of we might
是的，我知道这是闻所未闻的
actually be able to talk to people
真正能够与人交谈
during these calls yeah okay so a good
在这些通话中，是的，很好
thing I'm a little long-winded I guess
我猜我有点long
let me see if I can go ahead and share
让我看看我是否可以继续分享
all right is everyone seeing my screen
好吧，每个人都在看我的屏幕
yep okay so the that you know the
是的，所以你知道
Jakarta eat job X transition
雅加达吃工作X过渡
conversations largely died down in the
对话在很大程度上消失了
community but I do think there's an
社区，但我确实认为
important aspect that we're missing in
我们缺少的重要方面
the conversation because we've become
对话，因为我们已经成为
you know focused on on Big Bang versus
你知道专注于大爆炸与
incremental but it's important to
增量，但重要的是
remember that in the definition of Big
记住在大的定义中
Bang there's still the option for us not
还有我们没有的选择
to move everything and there are really
移动一切，真的有
good reasons to do that and that that
这样做的充分理由
that's an important conversation to have
那是一次重要的对话
that comes for free in the incremental
在增量版本中免费提供
perspective but if you have a Big Bang
的角度来看，但是如果你有一个大爆炸
mindset you still need to keep in mind
您仍然需要牢记的心态
some aspects that people have that are
人们拥有的一些方面是
issues that we can address by not moving
我们可以通过不动而解决的问题
everything one is that you know we know
一切都是你知道我们知道
there's a cost to legacy right there's a
遗产的代价是
lot of stuff that people don't even know
人们甚至不知道的很多东西
about that they don't use and and the
关于他们不使用和
quote I don't need that is a very big
引用我不需要那是一个很大的
thing that people like to throw at Java
人们喜欢扔给Java的东西
EE now Jakari EE so you know just
EE现在是Jakari EE，所以您知道
because something is there does do we
因为那里确实有我们
need to actually refresh it and move it
需要实际刷新并移动它
into the Jakarta namespace or is it fine
进入Jakarta名称空间还是可以的
living forever the rest of its days in
永远活在当下
Java X the other aspect is size
Java X的另一个方面是大小
you will often say things like Java EE
您会经常说诸如Java EE之类的话
is too big
太大了
this is our opportunity to address that
这是我们解决这个问题的机会
kind of concept and you know maybe some
一种概念，您可能知道一些
things just stay where they are and the
事情就留在原地，
other important thing to remember is
要记住的另一重要事项是
that just because we don't move it to
只是因为我们不将其移至
Jakarta doesn't mean it's dead it means
雅加达并不意味着它已经死了，而是意味着
we just don't see any reason that it
我们只是看不到任何原因
needs to evolve and it can continue to
需要发展，它可以继续
run just fine under Java X and so just
在Java X下可以正常运行，所以
because something doesn't move doesn't
因为不动不动
mean you can't use it anymore
意味着您不能再使用它
it means you're not going to have to
这意味着您将不必
invest in actually updating that code if
投资于实际更新该代码，如果
it's old and fine and doesn't need to be
它又旧又好，不需要
messed with
搞砸了
so to make this you know kind of a more
因此，使您知道更多
pragmatic conversation I wanted to
我想进行务实的谈话
highlight four specifications that that
强调四个规范
make this commerce the necessity for
使这项交易成为
this conversation far more obvious okay
这次谈话更明显好吗
so the first one is Java X Enterprise
所以第一个是Java X Enterprise
deploy it's a package it was created in
部署它是在其中创建的一个包
2000 it was proposed in 2000 and
2000年提出于2000年，
released in 2002 and it never moves
于2002年发布，从未动摇
beyond one point oh okay it was its
超过了一点，好吧，这是
point was to try and create a standard
重点是尝试创建一个标准
way to deploy into a java ee platform
部署到Java EE平台中的方法
and it never really took off beyond its
它从未真正起飞过
usage in the TCK itself it doesn't
在TCK本身中的用法
support any kind of you know nope no
支持任何你知道的不
cloud platform support this it's not
云平台支持这不是
Mountain used in any modern way a modern
以任何现代方式使用的山
perspective of this concept of doing a
做这个概念的观点
standardized deployment API would
标准化部署API将
involve some REST API and it definitely
涉及一些REST API，它肯定
would not look like the Java Enterprise
看起来不像Java Enterprise
deploy package the second aspect of it
部署程序包的第二个方面
is it occupies a namespace that is
它是否占用一个命名空间
largely you know where CDI lives
您基本上都知道CDI住在哪里
everything CEI lives under Java X
CEI在Java X下的一切
Enterprise and there is Java Enterprise
企业，还有Java企业
deploy snaring with CDI go and hey you
用CDI部署naring嘿
don't mind if I squat here for a while
不要介意我在这里蹲一会儿
the question is do we want to move this
问题是我们是否要移动这个
specification
规格
from job X enterprise into Jakarta
从工作X企业到雅加达
enterprise and still have it sitting
企业，仍然坐着
there grabbing some land from CDI and
从CDI那里抢了一些土地，
the concurrency utilities which is also
并发实用程序
under job X Enterprise concurrency now
现在在作业X Enterprise并发下
you know that's an important aspect of
你知道这是一个重要的方面
the conversation if we were to do an
如果我们要进行对话
actual enterprise deploy API we would
实际的企业部署API，我们将
want support from cloud vendors we would
需要云供应商的支持，我们将
want to do it fresh and and if we move
想重新做，如果我们搬家
this legacy API into Jakarta Enterprise
将此传统API集成到Jakarta Enterprise中
deploy what package would be used for
部署将用于什么软件包
the newer API and how would we explain
较新的API，我们将如何解释
the difference to people well the
对人的好处
Jakarta Enterprise deploys all legacy
Jakarta Enterprise部署了所有旧版
but the Jakara Enterprise even better
但是Jakara Enterprise甚至更好
package is is the one you should be
包是你应该的
using how do we tell people this another
使用我们如何告诉别人
aspect of it is Java X management j2ee
它的方面是Java X Management j2ee
this is jsr 77 proposed in 2000 and
这是2000年提出的jsr 77，
released in 2003 not updated for 13
2003年发布，未更新13
years not even a maintenance revision in
年甚至没有维护修订
13 years it was a JMX based way to get
13年以来，这是基于JMX的获取方式
stats from you know a Java EE
您了解的统计信息了解Java EE
implementation and um you know a modern
实施，你知道现代
perspective on this would use a REST API
对此的观点将使用REST API
and it would look a lot like micro
它看起来很像微型
profile metrics for example you know is
例如您知道的个人资料指标
this something that we need to be
这是我们需要做的
migrating from Jakarta to from Java x2
从雅加达迁移到Java x2
jacquard is there enough value there
提花那里有足够的价值
that it's worth explaining and talking
值得解释和讨论
about again or do we just leave it where
再说一次，还是我们把它留在哪里
it is another specification which is you
这是另一个规范
know definitely legacy is jsr 101 the
知道遗产绝对是jsr 101
the java xml RPC package proposed in
提出的java xml RPC包
2000 released in 2002 it largely
2000年发布，2002年发布
reflects the industry's first attempt at
反映了该行业在
soap services and was immediately
肥皂服务，并立即
deprecated by jax-ws in 2005 and census
jax-ws在2005年和普查中已弃用
base you know that was 13 years ago and
你知道那是13年前
jax-ws
jax-ws
has been the dominant way to do soap for
一直是肥皂的主要方式
Java EE in the last you know 13 years if
Java EE在过去的13年中
you're using soap in you know in Java EE
您在Java EE中使用肥皂
it is probably jax-ws if you have any
如果有的话，可能是jax-ws
old Jax RPC api's why would we want
旧的Jax RPC API是为什么我们想要
what's the justification for us making
我们做的理由是什么
you change that code right
您可以正确更改该代码
is there a justification there what
有理由吗
value do we create for you by having us
让我们为您创造价值
move that code and you have to spend
移动该代码，您必须花费
effort and updating you know you're not
努力和更新，您知道自己不是
going to be writing more applications in
将要编写更多的应用程序
that you're gonna be using jax-ws if you
如果您要使用jax-ws
are using soap so do we need to migrate
在用肥皂，所以我们需要迁移
this API or do we leave it calmly fine
这个API还是我们让它平静下来
and frozen the way it is another and the
并冻结了另一种方式
fourth and last API that I'm going to
我要使用的第四个也是最后一个API
talk about is java xml registry this is
谈论的是java xml注册表，这是
Jace r93 it's also another very very old
杰斯r93它也是另一个非常古老的
API it was only developed for a year and
API，仅开发了一年，
a half so it was proposed in 2001
所以是2001年提出的一半
received a year and a half of our
收到了我们一年半的时间
attention released in 2003 and after
2003年及之后发布的关注
that year and a half of initial push it
最初推销那一年半
wasn't touched
没有被感动
not even for maintenance releases for 17
甚至没有17的维护版本
years its goal was to try and create an
年的目标是尝试创建一个
API that would allow tools and us all to
允许工具和我们所有人使用的API
create an ecosystem around uddi and
在uddi周围建立生态系统，
things like that which is basically a
像这样的东西基本上是
way to register soap services in a
注册肥皂服务的方式
central location so they can be
中央位置，所以他们可以
discovered and looked up that industry
发现并查找了该行业
never really formed and argue that if
从来没有真正形成过，并认为如果
there is any implementation of a tool
有工具的任何实现
out there that leverages this API it is
可以利用这个API
17 years old and would likely be broken
17岁，可能会受伤
and forever lost if we were to migrate
如果我们要迁移，就会永远失去
this API so changing this package of
该API，因此更改了
this particular spec would likely result
该特定规格可能会导致
in the death of any implementations that
在任何实现的失败
are leveraging this
在利用这个
and so you know if we do think that this
所以你知道我们是否确实认为
thing has any value our best thing for
东西有什么价值，我们最好的东西
it is probably to leave it where it is
它可能会留在原地
and so you know that is a is a very
所以你知道那是一个非常
critical data point we can't just simply
关键数据点我们不能只是简单地
go everything's got to be changed so I
去一切都必须改变，所以我
think the the summary of this is that
认为总结是
Big Bang versus incremental is not the
大爆炸vs增量不是
most important part of the discussion it
讨论中最重要的部分
is an important part of the discussion
是讨论的重要部分
and the concept of Big Bang is we're not
而大爆炸的概念是我们不是
going to keep moving things over and
继续移动东西，
over and over again for the next 20
接下来的20遍
years we're gonna make a decision now
年，我们现在要做出决定
and we're going to stick to it but that
我们将坚持下去，但是那
decision doesn't necessarily mean we
决定并不一定意味着我们
have to or should move everything we do
必须或应该移动我们所做的一切
have legacy we need to talk about so we
有我们需要谈论的遗产，所以我们
need to audit each specs relevance and
需要审核每个规范的相关性，
figure out is this something that needs
找出这是需要的东西
to be expanded and improved in which
在其中进行扩展和改进
case it should move into Jakarta or is
如果它应该进入雅加达或
it fine as it is and maybe we just leave
很好，也许我们就走
it in Java X and it can still be part of
在Java X中仍然可以使用
the platform but we do not intend to
该平台，但我们不打算
migrate to update this thing ever
迁移以更新这件事
also you know people say Java EE is is
你也知道人们说Java EE是
large and too big if we don't want them
如果我们不希望它们太大而太大
saying that about Jakarta EE now is the
说关于Jakarta EE现在是
time to address our size are there some
是时候解决我们的规模了
things that we have control over there
我们在那里控制的事情
are specifications under jacquard IE
是提花IE下的规格
that maybe we just want to let them sit
也许我们只是想让他们坐下
there and slowly phase them out and
在那里，逐步淘汰它们，
which case if we plan to phase them out
如果我们打算逐步淘汰它们
we should definitely not move them to
我们绝对不应该将它们移到
Jakarta namespace because that's a land
雅加达名称空间，因为这是一块土地
grab against the future of what we can
抓住我们所能做的未来
do think of namespaces as domain names
确实将名称空间视为域名
right they have value do we want to
他们有价值，我们想要
occupy the Jakarta namespace with a
占用雅加达名称空间
bunch of things we think are legacy and
一堆我们认为是遗留的东西
are not going anywhere or do we want to
不去任何地方或我们想
leave the Jakarta namespace for the
离开Jakarta名称空间
things which are definitely relevant
绝对重要的事情
even a little relevant and you know new
甚至有点相关，你也知道新的
things but certain things that are very
事情，但是某些非常重要的事情
very legacy and old maybe they just stay
非常古老和古老，也许他们只是留下来
there in in the Java X namespace
在Java X名称空间中
and not move forward so that's the
而不是前进，那就是
summary of it so you know I that's all I
摘要，所以您知道我就是我
have prepared for this I do believe that
为此做好了准备，我相信
we need to facilitate this conversation
我们需要促进这种对话
better when we get through the judge
当我们通过法官时会更好
Accardi ee8 conversation you know
你知道的Accardi ee8对话
deliverables I'm sure we have to come
我相信我们一定要来
back and spend some time here and
回到这里并花一些时间
actually talk about each specification
实际谈论每个规范
but but that's that's the that's the
但这就是那个
update for now David there are two
现在更新大卫有两个
questions in the chat sure you want to
聊天中的问题确定您想要
address them now
现在解决他们
um it's difficult to read the chat let
嗯，很难阅读聊天记录
me yeah let me do that for you
我是的，让我为你做
so from John Kingman is the approach
所以从约翰·金曼（John Kingman）开始
that you're recommending deprecating
建议您弃用
those four specs in Jakarta e8 and
雅加达e8中的这四个规格
dropping them in Jakarta e9 and then
将它们放在Jakarta e9中，然后
comment drop or make optional - I would
发表评论或将其设为可选-我会
recommend we definitely do not so send a
建议我们绝对不要这样发送
question again rule just to make sure I
再问一个问题只是为了确保我
did got the first part of the sentence
确实得到了句子的第一部分
the first sentence so is the approach
第一句话也是方法
you're recommending deprecating those
您建议弃用那些
four specs in Jakarta e8 and dropping
雅加达e8中的四个规格下降
them in Jakarta e9 i would definitely
他们在雅加达e9我肯定
recommend deprecating javac
建议不推荐使用javac
because it's not used anywhere and
因为它没有在任何地方使用
Jack's are the last when we showed
杰克是我们表演的最后一个
Jack's RPC is already deprecated and
杰克的RPC已被弃用，
that's kind of a good point to note is
值得注意的一点是
that because it's already deprecated why
那是因为它已经被弃用了
would we move it to Jakarta and then
我们将其移至雅加达，然后
that leaves the javac' enterprise deploy
使得javac的企业部署
package and deprecating that is has
打包并弃用具有
always been impossible because the TC
总是不可能的，因为TC
cave uses it to do all the deploys and
洞穴使用它来进行所有部署，
so we you know we could say it's
所以我们知道我们可以说是
deprecated but in fact we would all
已弃用，但实际上我们都会
still have to support it until it's
仍然需要支持它，直到
replaced
已取代
so three of the four yes and one of
所以是四个是三个，另一个是
those is are in one of those three is
那是那三者之一
already deprecated and the fourth is not
已经不推荐使用，第四个不推荐使用
able to be deprecated but I do believe
可以弃用，但我相信
that none of the four should be moved
四个都不该动
into Jakarta namespace they don't
他们没有进入雅加达命名空间
provide enough value to occupy you know
提供足够的价值来占据你所知道的
our future namespace what was the second
我们未来的命名空间是第二个
question so let me now see the the chat
问题，现在让我看看聊天记录
is now going on and if people are on the
现在正在进行中，如果有人在
call you can go off mute yes Martin do
打电话给你可以静音，马丁可以
you want to unmute and ask the questions
您想取消静音并提出问题
so there was also comments on the
所以也有关于
terminology whether to make you know
术语是否让您知道
dropping api's or make them optional or
删除api或将其设为可选或
pruning so this is this is something
修剪所以这就是这个
that definitely requires wider
那肯定需要更广泛
discussion and some more organized way
讨论和一些更有组织的方式
of collecting input martin did you want
您想要收集输入马丁
to jump in yeah I can so basically I'm
跳进去，我基本上可以做到
asking how would you suggest that we
问您如何建议我们
could all date each sex relevance I
都可以跟每个性别相关的日期
think you know there's 34 specifications
认为您知道34种规格
there's 34 packages Java packages and
有34个Java包
you know I think what we need to do is
你知道我认为我们需要做的是
kind of divide and conquer get people to
一种分而治之的方法使人们
write up we need to do an analysis of
写出来，我们需要做一个分析
how long it's been since these some of
自从这些
these have changed I particularly I
这些改变了我，特别是我
would like to do a binary level analysis
想做一个二进制级别的分析
because in the JCP process a lot of
因为在JCP流程中
these things have received maintenance
这些东西已经得到维护
updates to change text in the
更新以更改
specification and things like that but
规格之类的东西，但是
at a binary level the API has stopped
在二进制级别，API已停止
moving at a certain date
在某个日期移动
what is that date and so you know
那是几号，所以你知道
getting some help analyzing when was the
在分析何时
last time we saw the method signatures
上次我们看到方法签名
of this ape
这个猿
change that's that's an important thing
改变那是很重要的
to know so what one of the things that
知道那么一件事
could be done is to take these 34
可以采取的是采取这34
packages that our honor or our control
包我们的荣誉或我们的控制
and you know do it like a binary diff
而且你知道它像二进制差异
did this thing change between you know
你知道这件事改变了吗
Java EE 8 and Java EE 7 Java EE 7 versus
Java EE 8和Java EE 7 Java EE 7与
Java EE 6 5 4 so on and figure out okay
Java EE 6 5 4等，然后确定
well this one hasn't been updated for 17
好吧，这个还没有更新17
years is there any value in it anymore
年已经没有任何价值了
you know
你懂
does it matter people using it is there
人们在那里使用它重要吗
any value of it to be you know moved in
您知道它的任何价值
the to the Jakarta namespace so you know
到Jakarta命名空间，所以您知道
that would be something that if people
如果人们
are if someone is willing to help do a
是否有人愿意帮忙做一个
binary diff let's coordinate on the
二进制差异让我们协调
jacquard EEE platform list and figure
提花EEE平台列表和图
out how to get that done we're
知道如何做到这一点，我们
collecting a lot of data there in the
在那里收集了大量数据
jacquard platforms best you know a
提花平台
project on the namespace transition
在名称空间过渡上的项目
there is a dependency tree that's there
有一个依赖树
people have contributed graphs based
人们贡献了基于图
upon that dependency information so I
基于该依赖性信息，所以我
think this is a this is a data point
认为这是一个数据点
that we haven't collected that we do
我们还没有收集到我们所做的
need to collect so that would be you
需要收集，以便成为你
know one way to to really get a new
知道真正获得新的方法
piece of information into this
这条信息
conversation that can help solve decide
有助于解决问题的对话
is this legacy or not and thank you I
是这个遗产还是谢谢我
fully agree like these things I don't
我完全不同意这些东西
like other than my career so some way
像我职业以外的其他方式
how to like you really separate this
怎么喜欢你才真正分开
would be necessary but I think that this
将是必要的，但我认为这
is a signal to the big vendors is
给大厂商的信号是
incremental collation you're right so
正确的增量整理
big bank versus incremental Big Bang you
大银行与增量大爆炸
know if we all decided tomorrow we're
知道我们是否都决定明天我们会
gonna do Big Bang if you look at the
如果你看着大爆炸
description of Big Bang it says okay now
Big Bang的描述现在说还可以
the follow-on discussion is what do we
后续讨论是我们做什么
want to migrate and what we want to
想迁移以及我们想要
leave there in Java X and and then
在Java X中留在那里，然后
obviously with incremental we're having
显然，增量式
the same conversation
相同的对话
but we're having a conversation from
但是我们正在与
where one a change as little as possible
尽可能少地改变
from Java to Jakarta and BIGBANG is sort
从Java到Jakarta和BIGBANG都是这样
of we want to change as much as possible
我们想要尽可能地改变
- the things that our legacy
-我们遗留下来的东西
so they both involve the same
所以他们都涉及相同的
conversation and the conversation of it
对话及其对话
is orthogonal to BIGBANG and even if you
与BIGBANG正交，即使您
are thinking in a Big Bang or
在大爆炸中思考或
incremental way you should still want to
您应该仍然希望采用增量方式
have this conversation because it's
进行对话是因为
relevant to either okay thank you thanks
与其中任何一个都有关，谢谢谢谢
David
大卫
okay if there are no more questions
好的，如果没有其他问题了
immediately then I'll take over to talk
马上我会接管
about upcoming conferences we're working
关于我们正在开展的即将召开的会议
on let me just try to share my screen so
让我尝试分享我的屏幕，这样
we are working on preparing two
我们正在准备两个
conferences so it's a Jakarta one
会议，所以这是雅加达会议
livestream I hope you've heard about
直播，希望您听说过
that one in last couple of months and
最后几个月的那个
also Eclipse con Europe 2019 so a little
还有Eclipse con Europe 2019有点
bit about Jakarta one livestream so it
关于雅加达的一个直播节目
is going to be a virtual one-day
将是虚拟的一天
conference that is dedicated to clouds
专门针对云的会议
native topics and in particular Jakarta
本地主题，尤其是雅加达
ie Java EE micro profile the date is the
即Java EE微型配置文件的日期为
September 10th 2019 and I will show you
2019年9月10日，我将向您展示
the website were continuously working on
该网站一直在努力
this is it sits right now open for
这是它现在就开放
registration we basically want to get a
注册我们基本上想得到一个
sense of draw people's attention and get
吸引人的注意力并获得感觉
a sense of how many people we will have
对我们将拥有多少人的感觉
diving in on that day we already had
那天我们已经潜水了
call for papers and it was closed on the
征集论文，并在
15th so this Monday we got around a
15日，所以这个星期一
little bit less than 50 talks and the
少于50次演讲，
program committee is now reviewing those
计划委员会现在正在审查那些
talks what we plan to have is is
谈论我们计划拥有的是
combination of keynote talks demos
主题演讲演示的组合
discussions and we're working on
讨论，我们正在努力
figuring out the schedule and as soon as
弄清楚时间表，并尽快
we have that we will publish it on the
我们有将其发布在
website as well of course we will be
网站以及我们当然会
tweeting and and asking for your help to
发推文并寻求您的帮助
spread the word and hopefully we will
传播这个词，希望我们会
make this event a success so there is
使这次活动取得成功，所以有
that is pretty much at this point
在这一点上差不多
everything I have to share with regards
我要分享的一切
to Jakarta Yee sorry Jakarta one live
致雅加达怡然雅加达一住
stream and yeah that would be it
流，是的，就是这样
the second conference that we are
我们是第二次会议
working on is Eclipse conure it is
正在工作的是Eclipse conure
scheduled for October 21st to the 24th
定于10月21日至24日
and it is in Germany ludwigsburg we are
在德国路德维希堡，我们是
going to have the I will go to the
我要去了
website again and show you so here
再次在网站上显示您的信息
here's the website and here are the
这是网站，这是
details were that you can find we are
细节是你可以找到我们
also now have a call for papers closed
现在也呼吁关闭文件
so far this was the largest number of
到目前为止，这是数量最多的
talks submissions in the area of the
讨论在该地区的意见书
cloud native I'll just show you the
云原生，我只向您展示
cloud tracks so it seems there that
云迹，所以似乎在那里
there is definitely a lot of interest a
肯定有很多兴趣
lot of great talks on this one as well
在这一方面也有很多精彩的演讲
so the invite is really for you to
所以邀请真的很适合你
register
寄存器
and figure out the accommodations
并找出住宿
because you know through the in last few
因为你通过最近的几个知道
years we're realizing it sells out
年，我们意识到它卖光了
pretty quickly so please jump on and and
非常快，所以请继续前进，然后
register I would also want to point out
注册我也要指出
that we're working on community related
我们正在与社区相关的工作
events so we are going to work and start
活动，所以我们要开始工作
working very shortly on Jakarta or I
在雅加达或我工作不久
should say I should call it cloud native
应该说我应该称它为云原生
related Community Day and a community
相关的社区日和社区
evening I believe we already know the
晚上，我相信我们已经知道了
date for the day for both so Community
两者的日期，所以社区
Day is going to be Monday and then
那天是星期一，然后
community evening is planned for Tuesday
计划在星期二举行社区晚会
so we already had some exchanges on
所以我们已经进行了一些交流
Jakarta e-mailing community mailing list
雅加达电子邮件社区邮件列表
and people are eager and interested very
人们非常渴望和感兴趣
shortly we are going to start organizing
不久我们将开始组织
those and and this these community
这些和这些社区
events will be community driven and
活动将由社区推动，
community organized of course Eclipse
Eclipse当然组织的社区
Foundation will take part in it but
基金会将参与其中，但
primarily this is community days or
主要是在社区日
events organized for the community so
为社区组织的活动
your feedback and input will be
您的反馈和输入将是
essential here that is everything I have
这里至关重要的是我拥有的一切
for the conferences any questions or
对于会议有任何疑问或
comments
评论
okay so if nothing on the conference's
好吧，如果会议的内容没有
I'm hoping that we can take the rest of
我希望我们可以接受其余的
the time for other questions we have
我们还有其他问题的时间
people not just the people who presented
人们不只是提出问题的人
but other people very much involved in
但是其他人非常参与
the Jakarta working group and and
雅加达工作组和
various committees so we're welcoming
各个委员会，所以我们欢迎
questions and discussions on any of the
有关以下任何方面的问题和讨论
topics nothing you just quickly see the
话题什么都没有，你很快就会看到
chat if there are some questions I don't
聊天，如果我没有其他问题
think we had any there hey Anthony I
认为我们那里有任何嘿安东尼一世
have maybe a question about it gets gone
也许对此有疑问
others time and what if I register and
其他时间，如果我注册，该怎么办？
then later get accepted as a speaker so
然后后来被接受为演讲者，所以
I don't know the exact answer but if
我不知道确切的答案，但是如果
that happens then we'll you know you can
那会发生，那么我们会知道你可以
contact us to start with you can contact
联系我们开始就可以联系
me and we'll figure it out
我，我们会解决的
okay so that's all grace yeah yeah no
好吧，这就是恩典吧，是的，不是
problem okay thanks no problem
问题还可以，谢谢，没问题
question for people if the no one has
向人们提问，如果没有人
any questions please do people is there
有任何问题请有人在那里
something in particular that people
特别是那些人
would like to see in this call that you
希望在这次电话中看到您
think maybe isn't getting discussed it
认为也许没有得到讨论
covered you know what silence doesn't
掩盖你知道什么沉默不
mean that we're happy and once again
表示我们很高兴，再一次
this is Amelia everyone some Jesus also
这是阿米莉亚每个人都有耶稣
scared when I see people being silent it
当我看到人们保持沉默时感到害怕
means or there are no brains available
意味着或没有大脑
to provide valuable feedback or were
提供宝贵的反馈意见或
just so not care enough that we're like
只是不太在乎我们喜欢
just run with the flow what's going to
随流程一起运行
be or is something else guys come on
是或有其他人来
let's do better
让我们做得更好
hi this is Scott Marlowe can you hear me
嗨，这是斯科特·马洛（Scott Marlowe），你能听到我说话吗？
yep what so you know what one thing that
是的，所以你知道那件事是什么
I'm concerned about might come later
我担心以后会不会
with jihad or ee9 whether we do
无论是与圣战还是ee9
incremental a big bang and I don't I
爆炸大爆炸，我不是
don't
别
yeah we call seeing this discussed much
是的，我们呼吁看到很多讨论
a in an additional wave I guess is you
我猜是你
know when when we switch over to the new
知道何时我们切换到新的
educator namespace and there are maybe
教育者名称空间，也许有
third party artifacts and or
第三方人工制品和或
applications out there that are sort of
那里的应用程序
looking at the transition from Jabra X
看Jabra X的过渡
to jihad or name space and maybe some of
去圣战或命名空间，也许一些
these are I don't know some of the yeah
这些是我不知道的
some things that we all use it just yeah
我们都使用它的一些东西
it's going to be you know some of the
这将是你知道一些
friction will be some of these projects
摩擦将是其中的一些项目
let's just say I don't know Eclipse link
只是说我不知道​​Eclipse链接
or hibernate or other other ones you
或冬眠或其他你的
know will have some difficulty because
知道会有一些困难，因为
it's sort of like a fork for them and
对他们来说就像是叉子
they want to continue with the Jacana
他们想继续与贾卡纳
ee8 namespace
ee8名称空间
and also move into you know
并进入你知道的
incrementally forward either big bang or
逐步转发大爆炸或
incremental with this other Hort but
与其他霍特增量
it's you know it it's gonna you know it
是你知道这是要知道
could could be like an additional wave
可能像是另一波浪潮
of you know that impacts things out of
你们知道这会影响事物
the control of what we've been talking
我们一直在谈论的控制
about so I don't you know it's a concern
关于，所以我不知道这是一个问题
I don't think we need an action plan per
我认为我们不需要每个人的行动计划
se but if there is one way that helps
本身，但是如果有一种方法可以帮助
that more than the other I'm not sure I
比其他我不确定
mean incremental has less impact I guess
我认为平均增量的影响较小
but but from the point of view of these
但从这些角度来看
third-party jars you know I I don't
您知道的第三方罐子II
really know what you which is better and
真的知道你哪个更好
if others have opinions on that I'd be
如果别人对此有意见，我会
interested
有兴趣
yeah I know that I was trying to give a
是的，我知道我想给
little space for other people to chime
其他人鸣铃的空间很小
in before I came bubbling in I know I
在我冒泡之前，我知道我
know that like there's going you're
知道就像你要去
right there's going to be impact on
将会对...产生影响
communities around the Jakarta community
雅加达社区附近的社区
there's gonna be impact in the spring
春天会有影响
community is going to be impacted drop
社区将受到影响
wizard and basically anybody who uses
向导，基本上任何使用
these types of api's in their you know
您知道的这些类型的api
competitive platform like there's a lot
竞争平台很多
of people who have platforms that are
拥有平台的人
kind of competitors to Jakarta in a lot
雅加达的竞争对手很多
of way but they still use some of the
当然，但他们仍然使用一些
api's that are developed under the
在api下开发的api
Jakarta umbrella for more Java EE
雅加达雨伞可用于更多Java EE
umbrella and they're gonna be impacted
雨伞，它们会受到影响
and you you you hit the nail on the head
而你，你打在了头上
when you said the word fork because they
当你说叉子这个词时，因为他们
may decide not to migrate to the new API
可能决定不迁移到新API
and you know what happens then
然后你知道会发生什么
right and that does kind of raise a
对，这确实引起了
question of you know what do we
你的问题知道我们怎么办
what do we collectively want to do now
我们现在集体想做什么
obviously they don't have to migrate
显然，他们不必迁移
doesn't mean anything to us particularly
对我们没什么特别的意义
if they don't migrate we know we are
如果他们不迁移，我们就会知道
going to have to write create migration
将不得不写创建迁移
tools regardless and so you know that's
工具不管，所以你知道那是
up to them you know it is an aspect of
对他们来说，你知道这是一个方面
all of the puzzle and I would really
所有的难题，我会真的
like to hear from those people in this
喜欢在这听取那些人的意见
discussion I have a little bit of
讨论我有点
nervous energy that we're only hearing
我们只听到的神经能量
from the Jakarta ee people like the true
来自雅加达ee的人们喜欢真实的
jacquard ET people we need to be hearing
我们需要倾听的提花ET人
from me like the whole industry so I
像整个行业一样来自我
would like to hear more voices in the
希望听到更多的声音
discussion that we're having around the
我们围绕的讨论
namespace because we're not the only
命名空间，因为我们不是唯一的
ones affected question yeah
那些受影响的问题是的
like you said we are going to prune drop
就像你说的，我们要修剪
remove or deprecated some obsolete
删除或弃用一些过时的
specifications form the platform that
规范形成了平台
will mean that we break Becker's
意味着我们打破了贝克尔的
compatibility right well so I want to be
兼容性很好，所以我想成为
clear that the maybe we need to
清楚，也许我们需要
introduce a new word I used freeze so
介绍一个我用冻结的新词
there is the opportunity that it stays
有机会留下来
in the platform and is supported it's
在平台上并受支持
just simply still in the Java X
只是仍然在Java X中
namespace so we do have the option to
命名空间，因此我们可以选择
take specifications leave them in the
拿规格留在
full profile they're just not gonna be
完整的个人资料，他们只是不会
migrated from Java X to Jakarta that's
从Java X迁移到了雅加达
an option right so in which case we're
一个正确的选择，在这种情况下，我们
not breaking any backwards compatibility
不破坏任何向后兼容性
the backwards compatibility of them
它们的向后兼容性
stays and we simply don't have any back
留下来，我们简直没有任何退缩
any community compatibility tool
任何社区兼容工具
requirements for those legacy api's if
这些旧版API的要求，如果
you follow me
你跟着我
as I do so it also means then if you're
正如我这样做，这也意味着如果你
talking about profiles again in the full
完整地再次谈论个人资料
profile if they actually specifications
如果他们实际规格说明
because you always drag them out drag
因为你总是把它们拖出来
them along right so if they stay in the
他们沿着正确的方向，所以如果他们留在
full profile that for example all the
完整的个人资料，例如所有
application servers that are going to
将要使用的应用程序服务器
migrate with evolution of the platform
随着平台的发展而迁移
has to drag these along so is that I
必须拖动这些，所以我
don't know if that's going to be a
不知道那会不会是
problem I don't think the discussion
问题我不认为讨论
about Java EE or Jakarta is baked or not
有关Java EE或Jakarta的信息
because Spring Framework is also big I
因为Spring框架也很大
don't know if it's going to be a problem
不知道这是否会成为问题
but when dovey the point is you can
但是当做点重点时，你可以
decide in a nice way to drop things that
决定以一种不错的方式丢弃那些
we really don't usually make anymore in
我们通常通常不再
new applications and still catch 40 old
新的应用程序仍然可以捕获40个旧的
ones the main platforms is the answer
主要平台就是答案
but yeah so the concept of actually
但是，是的，实际上
deprecating thing is somewhat orthogonal
弃用的东西有点正交
to the do we move it or not but but just
我们是否要移动它，但只是
to address how we've handled deprecation
解决我们如何处理弃用问题
in the past
以往
typically it's me you know it's made
通常是我，你知道它是人造的
optional and the platform's that you
可选的，平台就是你
know have customers using that old API
知道有客户使用旧的API
will typically still support it and
通常仍会支持它，并且
others don't will often drop it and so
其他人不会经常丢弃它，所以
you know Jax RPC and CMP are two
你知道Jax RPC和CMP是两个
examples that were made optional in the
示例中的可选示例
last version of Java and I think you
Java的最新版本，我想你
have some typing going on there so
在那里打字
furphy maybe everybody could mute but
毛发也许每个人都可以静音，
anyway so cmp injects RPC were made
无论如何，所以cmp注入了RPC
optional for example on the opening GP
可选，例如在打开的GP上
side of the fence and Apache we still
篱笆和阿帕奇的一面，我们仍然
support CMT because we brought our C
支持CMT，因为我们带来了C
implementation on top of JP because
在JP之上实施，因为
there isn't really any legacy there for
那里真的没有任何遗产
us to get rid of
我们摆脱
but yeah you know in Jakarta eating nine
但是你知道在雅加达吃了九
and ten we could continue to make more
十个我们可以继续做更多
things optional which is slightly
可选的东西有点
different topic than should the
与主题不同的主题
namespace be migrated or not thank you
命名空间是否迁移谢谢
so we're approaching will probably can
所以我们正在接近将可能
squeeze another question but as we're
挤压另一个问题，但随着我们
approaching the top of the hour I just
快要到了
want to invite people to use the
想邀请人们使用
document that the media start and leave
记录媒体开始和离开的时间
suggestions in that document how we can
该文档中的建议
improve this needing you can also leave
改善这种需要，你也可以离开
questions that you would like to be
您想成为的问题
answered but we would appreciate if and
回答，但如果和
maybe that will be easier way to collect
也许那将是更容易的收集方式
feedback needing to invite people to to
需要邀请人们加入的反馈
actually let us know how we're getting
实际上让我们知道我们如何
the calls I will because John
我会打电话，因为约翰
cleanliness and vacation and also not
清洁和度假，也没有
able to speak away ask a question
能够说出来问一个问题
Java EE nine thoughts and plans because
Java EE的九个想法和计划是因为
we're working in Java 8 before eclipse
我们在Eclipse之前使用Java 8
what is going on with that that is so do
这是怎么回事
we have any answers or comments on that
我们对此有任何答案或评论
one okay so we can definitely use that
好的，所以我们绝对可以使用
one for our next goal
一个为我们的下一个目标
there are some thoughts about what's
关于什么是一些想法
going to be in Jakarta align in the
将在雅加达对齐
github space so maybe if anyone's
github空间，所以如果有人
interested you can look there for for
有兴趣的你可以在那里寻找
starters mm-hmm yeah I guess would add
初学者mm-hmm是的，我想会加上
that the jax-rs community is definitely
jax-rs社区绝对是
doing work and so there's probably a
做工作，所以可能有一个
handful of communities out there that
少数社区
are actively working on the next
正在积极致力于下一个
revision of the respect maybe like three
修订方面可能像三个
to three rings I know there's are a lot
到三个戒指，我知道有很多
of ideas on what could happen but I
关于可能发生的事情的想法，但我
think everyone's so focused right now in
认为每个人现在都专注于
Jakarta ee8 getting that out the door
雅加达EE8将其发布
that it's a little bit difficult to to
这有点难
to think about 9:00 we were thinking
想想我们正在考虑的9:00
about ee9 like a month and a half ago
大约一个半月前的ee9
but like this week and next we have to
但是像本周和下周一样，我们必须
get all 34 specifications up for vote
收集所有34个规格以进行投票
and make all the all the namespace all
并使所有的所有命名空间全部
the branding changes that are required
所需的品牌变更
and so everyone's basically heads down
所以每个人基本上都低着头
but I think maybe next month or the
但我认为可能是下个月或
month after that you know it's probably
在那之后的一个月，您可能知道
the great time to start talking about
是时候开始谈论了
what do we want to do for a jacquard ee9
我们想为提花ee9做些什么
so eight will be out the door within the
所以八个会在门外
next two months here hopefully so or
接下来的两个月希望如此
before September in September it has to
在9月的9月之前，
right Yeah right so basically we'll be
对是的所以基本上我们会
having this conversation in full swing
进行这场对话
and sometime at September
在九月的某个时候
so as we're at the top of the hour I
所以当我们处于工作高峰时
would like to thank you for everyone for
在此感谢大家
joining and participating and we'll talk
加入和参与，我们将谈
again next month Thank You Tanya thank
下个月再次感谢您Tanya谢谢
you bye bye all right thanks everybody
再见，再见，谢谢大家